[
  {
    "Question": "What is the longest movie ever made?",
    "Answer": "The Cure of Insomnia",
    "A": "Dances with Wolves",
    "B": "The Cure of Insomnia",
    "C": "Hamlet",
    "D": "The Stand",
    "Description": "The Cure for Insomnia (1987) is the longest movie ever made at a total running time of 85 hours (5,220 min). It premiered in its entirety at The School Of The Art Institute in Chicago, Illinois from January 31 to February 3, 1987, in one continuous showing."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What character in Monty Python and the Holy Grail insists that \"It's just a flesh wound\"?",
    "Answer": "Black Knight",
    "A": "King Arthur",
    "B": "Sir Lancelot",
    "C": "Roger the Shrubber",
    "D": "Black Knight",
    "Description": "After literally disarming the Black Knight, Arthur assumes the fight is over and kneels to offer a prayer of thanks. The Black Knight interrupts Arthur's prayer by kicking him in the side of the head and accusing him of cowardice. When Arthur points out the Black Knight's injuries, the Knight insists \"It's just a flesh wound!"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the first movie by Pixar to receive a rating higher than G in the United States?",
    "Answer": "The incredibles",
    "A": "Monsters Inc.",
    "B": "Toy Story",
    "C": "Finding Nemo",
    "D": "The incredibles",
    "Description": "The Incredibles received a PG rating for \"action violence\"."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What film features a fight scene in which Bruce Lee breaks Jackie Chan's neck?",
    "Answer": "Enter the Dragon",
    "A": "South Park: Bigger, Longer & Uncut",
    "B": "Enter the Dragon",
    "C": "Game of Death",
    "D": "The Big Brawl",
    "Description": "Jackie Chan makes a brief (uncredited) cameo appearance towards the end of Enter the Dragon in the big fight scene in the cave. Bruce Lee grabs his hair for a moment before breaking his neck."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the only Top Gun actor who didn't vomit while in the fighter jets?",
    "Answer": "Anthony Edwards",
    "A": "Tom Cruise",
    "B": "Val Kilmer",
    "C": "John Stockwell",
    "D": "Anthony Edwards",
    "Description": "Anthony Edwards, who plays goose, is the only actor who didn't vomit while in the fighter jets."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What year was the first Academy Awards ceremony held?",
    "Answer": "1929",
    "A": "1924",
    "B": "1929",
    "C": "1935",
    "D": "1941",
    "Description": "The very first Academy Awards ceremony was held in the Blossom Room of the Hollywood Roosevelt Hotel on May 16, 1929. There were 250 people in attendance, and tickets cost $10. Today, attendance at the Academy Awards is by invitation only -- no tickets are sold to the public."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What new award category was added to the Academy Awards in 2001?",
    "Answer": "Best Animated Feature",
    "A": "Best Foreign Language Film",
    "B": "Best Assistant Director",
    "C": "Best Animated Feature",
    "D": "Best Song",
    "Description": "In 2001, a new category was added to the Academy Awards: Best Animated Feature. Shrek took home the inaugural award, defeating Jimmy Neutron: Boy Genius and Monsters, Inc."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What gas is used to \"turbo\" cars in The Fast and the Furious?",
    "Answer": "Nitrous oxide",
    "A": "Nitrogen dioxide",
    "B": "Carbon monoxide",
    "C": "Sulfur dioxide",
    "D": "Nitrous oxide",
    "Description": "A nitrous oxide engine is an internal combustion engine in which oxygen for burning the fuel comes from the decomposition of nitrous oxide, N2O, rather than air. The system increases the engine's power output by allowing fuel to be burned at a higher-than-normal rate. In The Fast and the Furious, this gas is commonly referred to as \"nitrous\" or simply NOS."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many people does John Wick kill in movie John Wick?",
    "Answer": "77",
    "A": "34",
    "B": "128",
    "C": "53",
    "D": "77",
    "Description": "In John Wick, he kills 77 people, but he's just getting started. In John Wick: Chapter 2, he easily tops that with a body count of 128."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What does John McClane write on the first terrorist he kills in Die Hard?",
    "Answer": "Ho-Ho-Ho'",
    "A": "Merry Christmas'",
    "B": "Now It's a Party'",
    "C": "Yippee Ki-Yay'",
    "D": "Ho-Ho-Ho'",
    "Description": "John puts a Santa hat on the corpse, sits him on a chair and uses a red permanent marker to write: \"Now I have a machine gun. Ho Ho Ho."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In Colombiana, what \"signature\" does Cataleya leave behind after each of her assassinations?",
    "Answer": "A flower",
    "A": "A playing card",
    "B": "A half-smoked cigarette",
    "C": "a lipstick kiss",
    "D": "A flower",
    "Description": "With each murder she commits, she leaves her signature, the Cattleya flower, which is a message to her ultimate target, Don Luis, that she is coming for him."
  },
  {
    "Question": "When the sheriff pats him down in First Blood and finds his knife, what does Rambo say it's for?",
    "Answer": "Hunting",
    "A": "Trimming his nails",
    "B": "Self defence",
    "C": "whittling",
    "D": "Hunting",
    "Description": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who saves Grant, Ellie, and Hammond's grandchildren when they are cornered by Velociraptors at the end of Jurassic Park?",
    "Answer": "T. Rex",
    "A": "Wu",
    "B": "Malcom",
    "C": "T. Rex",
    "D": "Hammond",
    "Description": "When all hope is lost, the T. Rex comes crashing into the atrium and attacks the raptors, buying enough time for everyone to escape."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What kind of \"muttations\" do the Gamemakers release to intensify the final moments of The Hunger Games?",
    "Answer": "Wolf mutts",
    "A": "Monkey mutts",
    "B": "Bear mutts",
    "C": "Lizard mutts",
    "D": "Wolf mutts",
    "Description": "As the Hunger Games draw to a close, the Head Gamemaker releases a pack of wolf-like \"muttations\" on the final tributes. Eerily, each of the mutts resembles one of the tributes who has died."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where does Jack's compass point in Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl?",
    "Answer": "To whatever he wants most",
    "A": "Nowhere - it's broken",
    "B": "To the Isla de Muerta",
    "C": "To gold",
    "D": "To whatever he wants most",
    "Description": "Although it appears to be nothing more than a useless trinket, Jack's compass, which he bartered from the voodoo mystic Tia Dalma, points to whatever he desires most."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How old is the ruthless vigilante Hit-Girl in Kick-Ass (2010)?",
    "Answer": "11 years old",
    "A": "15 years old",
    "B": "9 years old",
    "C": "11 years old",
    "D": "13 years old",
    "Description": "Big Daddy (Nicolas Cage) is a former cop who, in his quest to bring down the crime boss Frank D'Amico and his son Red Mist, has trained his eleven-year-old daughter (ChloÃ« Grace Moretz) to be the ruthless vigilante Hit-Girl."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where does Sucker Punch (2011) take place?",
    "Answer": "Mental hospital",
    "A": "Prehistoric jungle",
    "B": "World War II battlefield",
    "C": "Mental hospital",
    "D": "Brothel",
    "Description": "The film stars Emily Browning as \"Babydoll,\" a young woman who is committed to a mental institution and copes by envisioning it as a brothel. She teams up with four dancers/prisoners to escape before her scheduled lobotomy."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What shows the crew of the Black Pearl as they really are in Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl?",
    "Answer": "Moonlight",
    "A": "Photographs",
    "B": "Sun,ight",
    "C": "Mirrors",
    "D": "Moonlight",
    "Description": "The crew has been cursed and become undead. Moonlight reveals them to be living, rotting skeletons."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the first of the children to discover Narnia?",
    "Answer": "Lucy",
    "A": "Lucy",
    "B": "Edmund",
    "C": "Susan",
    "D": "Peter",
    "Description": "Lucy is the first of the children to discover Narnia when she wanders through the wardrobe during a game of hide-and-seek. Edmund is second to make the journey, and finally all of the children travel to Narnia when they attempt to hide in the wardrobe after accidentally breaking a window."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who calls herself the \"Queen of Narnia\"?",
    "Answer": "The White Witch",
    "A": "Lucy",
    "B": "Susan",
    "C": "Mrs. Beaver",
    "D": "The White Witch",
    "Description": "The White Witch calls herself the \"Queen of Narnia.\" She is not, however, the rightful ruler."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How much does Rhett bid to dance with Scarlett in Gone With the Wind?",
    "Answer": "$150",
    "A": "$75",
    "B": "$25",
    "C": "$150",
    "D": "$300",
    "Description": "Rhett shocks the audience into silence by bidding $150 \"in gold\" for Scarlett as a dancing partner. Because she is in mourning, Rhett is told that it wouldn't be proper. But Scarlett scandalously accepts."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What Disney movie was the first full-length animated feature to be produced in the United States?",
    "Answer": "Snow White",
    "A": "Pinocchio",
    "B": "Steamboat Willie",
    "C": "Snow White",
    "D": "Bambi",
    "Description": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarf (1937) was the first full-length animated feature film to come out of the United States (the first ever was Die Abenteuer des Prinzen Achmed (1926), which clocks in at 65 minutes, and was animated entirely in silhouette)."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the only Disney animated feature film that has a title character who doesn't speak?",
    "Answer": "Dumbo",
    "A": "Lady & The Tramp",
    "B": "Dumbo",
    "C": "The Fox and the Hound",
    "D": "Lilo & Stitch",
    "Description": "Dumbo doesn't utter a single word during the movie."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What popular Disney character makes a cameo appearance as a stuffed animal in Frozen?",
    "Answer": "Mickey Mouse",
    "A": "Donald Duck",
    "B": "Stitch",
    "C": "Mickey Mouse",
    "D": "Dumbo",
    "Description": "Micky Mouse made a special appearance in Wandering Oaken's Trading Post and Sauna--in the form of a plush toy."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What does the little mermaid call the fork in her collection of human objects?",
    "Answer": "Dinglehopper",
    "A": "Dinglehopper",
    "B": "Snarfblatt",
    "C": "Wumbus",
    "D": "Sneedle",
    "Description": "Ariel displays the dinglehopper proudly in her undersea grotto."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the only character in Disney's Alice in Wonderland that did not appear in Lewis Carroll's books?",
    "Answer": "The Doorknob",
    "A": "Dormouse",
    "B": "Queen of Hearts",
    "C": "The Doorknob",
    "D": "Alice's sister",
    "Description": "The Doorknob was also one of the few characters in Wonderland to show any sympathy for Alice."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Disney princess?",
    "Answer": "Persephone",
    "A": "Snow White",
    "B": "Persephone",
    "C": "Cinderella",
    "D": "Aurora",
    "Description": "Although Snow White was Disney's first full-length movie princess, she wasn't the first Disney princess. That honor goes to Persephone, the main character of a 1934 Silly Symphonies short that served as a sort of test run for Snow White."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is Boo's real name in Monster's Inc.?",
    "Answer": "Mary",
    "A": "Alice",
    "B": "Mary",
    "C": "Suzie",
    "D": "Ashley",
    "Description": "Although her real name is never spoken out loud, she signs some of her drawings \"Mary\"."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which character in Frozen likes warm hugs?",
    "Answer": "Olaf",
    "A": "Kristoff",
    "B": "Anna",
    "C": "Elsa",
    "D": "Olaf",
    "Description": "Created from Elsa's magical powers, Olaf is the friendliest snowman in Arendelle. He is innocent, outgoing and likes warm hugs."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the first Disney animated film to feature a completely original storyline?",
    "Answer": "The Lion King",
    "A": "Lilo & Stitch",
    "B": "The Fox and the Hound",
    "C": "The Lion King",
    "D": "Moana",
    "Description": "The Lion King was billed as Disney's first animated feature that wasn't a retelling of another story or fairytale."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where is the entrance to Peter Pan's hideout?",
    "Answer": "Hangman's tree",
    "A": "Blindman's bluff",
    "B": "Cannibal cove",
    "C": "Mermaid lagoon",
    "D": "Hangman's tree",
    "Description": "The Hangman's Tree is an old tree, located deep within Neverland, with several hidden entrances that Peter and the Lost Boys use to enter and exit their hideout."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What Disney movie was the first full-length animated feature to be nominated for an Oscar for Best Picture?",
    "Answer": "Beauty and the Beast",
    "A": "Beauty and the Beast",
    "B": "The Lion King",
    "C": "Little Mermaid",
    "D": "The Jungle Book",
    "Description": "Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first full length animated feature to be nominated for an Oscar for Best Picture, losing to The Silence of the Lambs. It was also the first full-length animated feature to win the Golden Globe for Best Picture (Musical or Comedy)."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which Disney princess wears pants instead of a dress?",
    "Answer": "Jasmine",
    "A": "Elsa",
    "B": "Merida",
    "C": "Pocahontas",
    "D": "Jasmine",
    "Description": "Princess Jasmine's everyday outfit consists of a cropped off-the-shoulder top and matching aqua pants."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where does Aladdin live?",
    "Answer": "Agrabah",
    "A": "Ishtar",
    "B": "Qumar",
    "C": "Agrabah",
    "D": "Baghdad",
    "Description": "Agrabah was actually a stand-in for Baghdad, the city that Disney originally planned to be the movie's setting, before changing the name due to political issues that were occurring at the time."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many people associated with The Exorcist died during production?",
    "Answer": "9",
    "A": "12",
    "B": "9",
    "C": "3",
    "D": "6",
    "Description": "By the end of the film's production, nine people associated with its making had passed away, including Jack McGowran who played Burke Dennings, Linda Blair's grandfather, a night watchman on set, and a special effects expert."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the only character to appear in and survive all four Jaws movies?",
    "Answer": "Michael Brody",
    "A": "Sean Brody",
    "B": "Martin Brody",
    "C": "Ellen Brody",
    "D": "Michael Brody",
    "Description": "Michael Brody is the older brother of the late Sean Brody and the son of Chief Brody and Ellen Brody. He is a major character in Jaws, a supporting character in Jaws 2, and the main protagonist of Jaws 3-D and Jaws: The Revenge."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is unusual about the videotape in The Ring?",
    "Answer": "It doesn't include the code",
    "A": "It doesn't include the code",
    "B": "It won't burn in fire",
    "C": "It can't be copied",
    "D": "It's more than 100 years old",
    "Description": "The tape's overscan does not include time code, which suggests that it wasn't made using electronic equipment."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is responsible for releasing the deadly virus in 28 Days Later?",
    "Answer": "Animal Rights Activists",
    "A": "Islamic Terrorists",
    "B": "The Chinese Government",
    "C": "Animal Rights Activists",
    "D": "Taxi Driver",
    "Description": "A highly contagious, rage-inducing virus is unleashed in Great Britain after a group of animal rights activists attempt to free chimpanzees infected with the virus in Cambridge."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where does Friday the 13th take place?",
    "Answer": "Camp Crystal Lake",
    "A": "Camp Clear Lake",
    "B": "Camp Crescent Lake",
    "C": "Camp Kikiwaka",
    "D": "Camp Crystal Lake",
    "Description": "Camp Crystal Lake had 22 years of uninterrupted good times until a handicapped camper drowned in the summer of 1957, setting off string of grisly murders."
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Lord of the Rings movies are based on a novel by what author?",
    "Answer": "J.R.R Tolkien",
    "A": "J.K. Rowling",
    "B": "J.M. Barrie",
    "C": "H.G. Wells",
    "D": "J.R.R Tolkien",
    "Description": "A sequel to Tolkien's earlier novel (The Hobbit), The Lord of the Rings was published in three volumes from 1954 to 1955 and made into a very successful live-action feature film trilogy (2001-2003) by director Peter Jackson."
  },
  {
    "Question": "The only way to destroy the Ring of Power is to throw it into the fires of _________?",
    "Answer": "Mount Doom",
    "A": "Mount Zion",
    "B": "Mount Doom",
    "C": "Mount Mordor",
    "D": "Mount Moria",
    "Description": "The Dark Lord Sauron desperately wants the Ring of Power which will give him mastery over Middle-earth. The only way to destroy the Ring is to cast it back into the fires of Mount Doom where it was forged."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What does Gollum call the Ring of Power?",
    "Answer": "My Precious",
    "A": "My Darling",
    "B": "My Lovely",
    "C": "My Treasure",
    "D": "My Precious",
    "Description": "Centuries of the Ring's influence have twisted Gollum's body and mind, and he has come to call the Ring \"my precious\", illustrating his perversion from loving another living being to loving an object of power."
  },
  {
    "Question": "For what special occasion does Gandalf return to the Shire?",
    "Answer": "Bilbo's birthday",
    "A": "Bilbo's funeral",
    "B": "Bilbo's coronation",
    "C": "Bilbo's birthday",
    "D": "Bilbo's wedding",
    "Description": "Gandalf reunites with his old friend Bilbo at the Hobbit's 111st (pronounced \"eleventy first\") birthday party. When Bilbo uses the One Ring to vanish from his own party, playing a prank on his guests, Gandalf begins to suspect the Ring's true nature."
  },
  {
    "Question": "While traveling through the mines of Moria, which member of the Fellowship of the Ring is killed by the Balrog?",
    "Answer": "Gandalf",
    "A": "Boromir",
    "B": "Frodo",
    "C": "Gandalf",
    "D": "Aragorn",
    "Description": "As the Fellowship nears the end of its journey through the mines of Moria, they are attacked by a fire demon known as a Balrog. In order to buy the others time to escape, Gandalf engages the Balrog in battle. Although he dies during the course of the battle, Gandalf's life is later restored and he is returned to Middle-earth to complete his task."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the name of the Ent who carries Pippin and Merry through Fangorn Forest?",
    "Answer": "Treebeard",
    "A": "Greybranch",
    "B": "Quickbeam",
    "C": "Treebeard",
    "D": "Skinbark",
    "Description": "In The Two Towers, Pippin and Merry escape from their Orc captors only to be captured by an Ent named Treebeard. Although Treebeard crushes the lone Orc who is pursuing them, he still mistakes the two hobbits for \"little orcs\" and announces his intention to ask the White Wizard for advice on what to do with them. Fortunately for Pippin and Merry, the \"White Wizard\" turns out to be a resurrected Gandalf--not the evil Saruman."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who does Sam marry at the end of The Return of the King?",
    "Answer": "Rosie Cotton",
    "A": "Gilly Baggins",
    "B": "Pearly Bottom",
    "C": "Daisy Puddle",
    "D": "Rosie Cotton",
    "Description": "In The Fellowship of the Ring, Sam has a crush on Rosie Cotton, a barmaid at the Green Dragon pub, but he is too shy to talk to her. In The Return of the King, after he returns to the Shire, Sam, emboldened by his adventures, approaches Rosie and soon they are happily married."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which hero tries to steal the Ring from Frodo?",
    "Answer": "Boromir",
    "A": "Boromir",
    "B": "Gimli",
    "C": "Aragorn",
    "D": "Legolas",
    "Description": "Boromir dislikes the idea of destroying the One Ring, as he believes it could be used to defeat Sauron once and for all, to save Gondor, and return it to its former glory. He tries to convince Frodo to give him the Ring, and when this fails, tries to take it by force, but he redeems himself shortly thereafter when he gives his life to protect Marry and Pippin."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many Academy Awards did The Lord of the Rings trilogy win?",
    "Answer": "17",
    "A": "11",
    "B": "17",
    "C": "4",
    "D": "7",
    "Description": "The trilogy won a total of seventeen Academy Awards: four for The Fellowship of the Ring, two for The Two Towers, and eleven for The Return of the King. The Return of the King won every Oscar for which it was nominated, including Best Picture, and tied Titanic (1997) and Ben-Hur(1959) for the most Oscars awarded to one film."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What kind of doctor is Stephen Strange?",
    "Answer": "Neurosurgeon",
    "A": "Neurosurgeon",
    "B": "Plastic surgeon",
    "C": "Pediatric surgeon",
    "D": "Orthopedic surgeon",
    "Description": "Before he became Master of the Mystic Arts, Doctor Strange was a brilliant neurosurgeon."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who destroys Thor's hammer?",
    "Answer": "Hela",
    "A": "Hela",
    "B": "Loki",
    "C": "Ultron",
    "D": "Thanos",
    "Description": "In Thor: Ragnarok, Hela orders her younger brothers to kneel down before her. Thor defiantly hurls MjÃ¸lnir at her, but Hela, who was the hammer's first wielder, catches it in mid-air and destroys it with her bare hands."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What kingdom does the Black Panther rule?",
    "Answer": "Wakanda",
    "A": "Genosha",
    "B": "Sokovia",
    "C": "Krakoa",
    "D": "Wakanda",
    "Description": "T'Challa is officially crowned King of Wakanda after his father's death. As the Wakandan monarch, he also inherits the mantle of the Black Panther."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In Ant-Man, what hero disappears into a subatomic quantum realm while disabling a Soviet nuclear missile?",
    "Answer": "Wasp",
    "A": "Wasp",
    "B": "Yellojacket",
    "C": "Ant-Man",
    "D": "Atom",
    "Description": "In a flashback, Janet van Dyne (a.k.a. the Wasp) sacrifices herself to disarm a Soviet ICBM bound for the United States and is presumed dead."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What metal is Wakanda's most precious resource?",
    "Answer": "Vibranium",
    "A": "Mithril",
    "B": "Vibranium",
    "C": "Adamantium",
    "D": "Dilithium",
    "Description": "Millions of years ago a meteorite made of vibranium, the strongest substance in the universe struck the continent of Africa, affecting the plant life around it, and when the time of men came five tribes settled on it and called it Wakanda."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which Avenger does Thor team up with in Thor: Ragnarok?",
    "Answer": "Hulk",
    "A": "Iron Man",
    "B": "Hawkeye",
    "C": "Captain America",
    "D": "Hulk",
    "Description": "Thor is forced to compete in the Grandmaster's Contest of Champions, facing his old pal--the Hulk."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What kind of war animal is bred by the Border Tribe in Black Panther?",
    "Answer": "Rhinos",
    "A": "Rhinos",
    "B": "Lions",
    "C": "Elephants",
    "D": "Panthers",
    "Description": "During the Battle of Mount Bashenga, W'Kabi calls for the Border Tribe's war rhinoceroses. Thanks to these reinforcements, the Border Tribe gains the upper hand against the Dora Milaje until Okoye stands in front of a charging rhino and saves M'Baku's life."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where did Captain Marvel get her powers?",
    "Answer": "From a light-speed engine",
    "A": "From the skrulls",
    "B": "From a light-speed engine",
    "C": "From the supreme intelligence",
    "D": "she was born with them",
    "Description": "She obtained cosmic powers upon being exposed to the energy of the Tesseract via the destruction of a light-speed engine."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Jurassic Park is based on a book by which author?",
    "Answer": "Michael Crichton",
    "A": "Stephen King",
    "B": "Michael Crichton",
    "C": "Isaac Asimov",
    "D": "Philip K. Dick",
    "Description": "Before Jurassic Park was even published, Crichton demanded a non-negotiable fee of $1.5 million for the film rights from Universal."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the biggest scientific inaccuracy in The Martian?",
    "Answer": "The massive windstorm",
    "A": "Using RTG as a portable heat source",
    "B": "Using EVA suit like iron man glove",
    "C": "Growing potatoes in martian soil",
    "D": "The massive windstorm",
    "Description": "While The Martian gets much of its science right, the massive windstorm that sets the story in motion and leaves Mark Watney stranded on Mars is scientifically inaccurate. Since Mars' atmospheric pressure is so low, even a fierce storm like the one shown would do little more than mess up your hair."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which real-life NASA probe does Mark Watney hack in The Martian?",
    "Answer": "Pathfinder",
    "A": "Pathfinder",
    "B": "Opportunity",
    "C": "Sojourner",
    "D": "Spirit",
    "Description": "Watney interacts with several real-life pieces of existing technology, including a real-life NASA probe: Mars Pathfinder. Using Pathfinder's camera and motor, he establishes rudimentary two-way communication with Earth, first using hand-written signs, and then sending and receiving ASCII in hexadecimal."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the synthetic humans in Blade Runner called?",
    "Answer": "Replicants",
    "A": "Moravecs",
    "B": "Replicants",
    "C": "Synths",
    "D": "Androids",
    "Description": "The Nexus-series of replicants are virtually identical to adult humans but have superior strength, speed, agility, resilience, and intelligence, to varying degrees depending on the model."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the name of the company Neo works for in The Matrix?",
    "Answer": "MetaCortex",
    "A": "Dunder Mifflin",
    "B": "Oscorp",
    "C": "Cyberdyne Systems",
    "D": "MetaCortex",
    "Description": "On what might be his last day of employment at MetaCortex, Neo is reprimanded by his boss, Mr. Rhineheart, regarding his punctuality."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What moon are humans colonizing in Avatar?",
    "Answer": "Pandora",
    "A": "Phobos",
    "B": "Nereid",
    "C": "Pandora",
    "D": "Naiad",
    "Description": "The film is set in the mid-22nd century when humans are colonizing Pandora, a lush habitable moon orbiting Polyphemus, a fictional gas giant in the Alpha Centauri star system."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How long did it take to render each frame (1/24th of a second) of the CGI scenes in the movie Avatar?",
    "Answer": "47 hours",
    "A": "47 seconds",
    "B": "47 days",
    "C": "47 hours",
    "D": "47 minutes",
    "Description": "Each frame (1/24 of a second) of the CGI scenes in Avatar (2009) took an average of 47 hours to render."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is Walter White's alias in Breaking Bad?",
    "Answer": "Heisenberg",
    "A": "Heisenberg",
    "B": "Bloomberg",
    "C": "Hindenburg",
    "D": "Rosenberg",
    "Description": "As Walt is pulled deeper into the illicit drug trade, becoming more and more ruthless as the series progresses, he eventually transforms fully into his \"Heisenberg\" drug kingpin persona."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In Game of Thrones, What does Daenerys recieve as a wedding gift from Illyrio Mopatis?",
    "Answer": "Dragon eggs",
    "A": "Enchanted sword",
    "B": "Dragon eggs",
    "C": "Crystal ball",
    "D": "Magic wand",
    "Description": "Daenerys is given three apparently fossilized dragons eggs on the occasion of her wedding to Khal Drogo. After his death, she places the eggs next to Drogo and lights his funeral pyre, then steps into the flames herself. The next morning, she is found in the ashes, unharmed, flanked by three newly hatched dragons."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is Sterling Cooper's largest client in season one of Mad Men?",
    "Answer": "Lucky Strike",
    "A": "Philip Morris",
    "B": "Pall Mall",
    "C": "Lucky Strike",
    "D": "Marlboro",
    "Description": "As the series opens, the agency is working to reassure Lucky Strike, whose account is the firm's bread and butter, in the face of resurgent medical research demonstrating smoking is harmful and related lawsuits and impending legislation harmful to the tobacco industry."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In Stranger Things, what game does Will Byers play just before his abduction?",
    "Answer": "Dungeons & Dragons",
    "A": "Dragon's Lair",
    "B": "Dungeons & Dragons",
    "C": "Pokemon",
    "D": "Magic: The Gathering",
    "Description": "Will encounters the creature from the Upside Down and mysteriously vanishes while cycling home from a Dungeons & Dragons session with his friends Mike Wheeler, Dustin Henderson and Lucas Sinclair."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How does Rick get to Atlanta in the pilot episode of The Walking Dead?",
    "Answer": "On horseback",
    "A": "He walks",
    "B": "On horseback",
    "C": "By motorcycle",
    "D": "In a tank",
    "Description": "When he sets out for Atlanta where a refugee camp is rumored to exist, Rick runs out of gas and is forced to abandon his car. He continues the rest of the way on horseback."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the name of Michael Knight's car on Knight Rider?",
    "Answer": "Kitt",
    "A": "Christine",
    "B": "Hal 9000",
    "C": "General Lee",
    "D": "Kitt",
    "Description": "The character of KITT (Knight Industries Two Thousand) in the original Knight Rider series was physically embodied as a modified 1982 Pontiac Trans Am with numerous special features such as Turbo Boost, the ability to drive 'himself', a front mounted scanner bar that allowed KITT to 'see', and 'molecular bonded shell' body armor that was invulnerable to small arms fire, the impact of thrown objects, and even high speed impact with a cinder block wall."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which Breaking Bad character wasn't supposed to live past the first season?",
    "Answer": "Jesse Pinkman",
    "A": "Gretchen Schwartz",
    "B": "Marie Schrader",
    "C": "Skyler White",
    "D": "Jesse Pinkman",
    "Description": "Producer Vince Gilligan had originally planned to kill Jesse off during the original nine-episode arc, but he realized early on that it would be a huge mistake, and the show ultimately ended up being largely about the tumultuous partnership between Walter White and his former student."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which small midwestern town does Stranger Things take place?",
    "Answer": "Hawkins",
    "A": "Storybrooke",
    "B": "Evansville",
    "C": "Oakdale",
    "D": "Hawkins",
    "Description": "Prior to 1983, Hawkins, Indiana was a largely quiet and uneventful town. The greatest point of interest was the secretive Hawkins National Laboratory, one of several national laboratories which grew out of the scientific endeavors of World War II. Unknown to the residents of the town, the lab was contributing to the controversial government program known as MKUltra."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the Police Chief in Stranger Things?",
    "Answer": "Hopper",
    "A": "Holloway",
    "B": "Hopper",
    "C": "Callahan",
    "D": "Powell",
    "Description": "Hopper doesn't seem to care much about his job, as he regularly sleeps in and drinks and shows up late for work. It isn't until Will Byers goes missing and he discovers some sort of government cover-up that Hopper begins to take his job seriously."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which character becomes a wanted fugitive during the final season of The Office?",
    "Answer": "Creed",
    "A": "Creed",
    "B": "Andy",
    "C": "Dwight",
    "D": "Michael",
    "Description": "After becoming a wanted fugitive, Creed fakes his own death, only to be discovered living at the office in Ryan's old closet. Creed sings a song on the guitar for the office before being arrested."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which character on The Office was originally an assistant casting director on the show?",
    "Answer": "Phyllis Vance",
    "A": "Angela Martin",
    "B": "Stanley Hudson",
    "C": "Kevin Malone",
    "D": "Phyllis Vance",
    "Description": "Phyllis Smith was initially a casting associate for the show, but producers loved her so much while she was reading lines with other actors during auditions that she was offered the role of soft-spoken saleswoman Phyllis Vance, a character created specifically for her."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the real name of Marcel the monkey from Friends?",
    "Answer": "Katie",
    "A": "Boo",
    "B": "Jack",
    "C": "Katie",
    "D": "Binks",
    "Description": "Marcel the monkey is actually a female and her name is Katie."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which character on The Big Bang Theory suffers from selective mutism?",
    "Answer": "Raj",
    "A": "Leonard",
    "B": "Raj",
    "C": "Howard",
    "D": "Stuart",
    "Description": "Raj is unable to speak in front of women outside his own family due to selective mutism--unless he's drunk, in which case he says very inappropriate things."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which Star Trek captain has an artificial heart?",
    "Answer": "Jean-Luc Picard",
    "A": "Jonathan Archer",
    "B": "Benjamin Sisko",
    "C": "Kathryn Janeway",
    "D": "Jean-Luc Picard",
    "Description": "In 2327, Jean-Luc Picard received an artificial heart after he was stabbed by a Nausicaan during a bar brawl."
  },
  {
    "Question": "HBO's Game of Thrones is adapted from what series of novels?",
    "Answer": "A Song of Ice and Fire",
    "A": "The Kingkiller Chronicle",
    "B": "Earthsea",
    "C": "A Song of Ice and Fire",
    "D": "The Broken Empire",
    "Description": "HBO's Game of Thrones is adapted from what series of novels?"
  },
  {
    "Question": "On which continent are the Seven Kingdoms located in Game of Thrones?",
    "Answer": "Westeros",
    "A": "Hyboria",
    "B": "Westeros",
    "C": "Valyria",
    "D": "Essos",
    "Description": "A major arc concerns the Iron Throne of the Seven Kingdoms of Westeros through a web of political conflicts among the noble families either vying to claim the throne or fighting for independence from it."
  },
  {
    "Question": "In Game of Thrones, what military order defends the realm against threats from the North?",
    "Answer": "Night's Watch",
    "A": "Knights of the Vale",
    "B": "Iron Fleet",
    "C": "Night's Watch",
    "D": "Dothraki",
    "Description": "The Night's Watch guards the Wall to keep the wildlings and White Walkers from crossing into the Seven Kingdoms."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which Lannister is a dwarf?",
    "Answer": "Tyrion",
    "A": "Tywin",
    "B": "Cersei",
    "C": "Jaime",
    "D": "Tyrion",
    "Description": "A commoner born with dwarfism would have been left in the woods to die. Luckily for Tyrion, his birthright as a Lannister not only saved his life, but afforded him significant wealth and power."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How does Jaime Lannister cripple Bran Stark?",
    "Answer": "Pushes him from a window",
    "A": "Pushes him from a window",
    "B": "Breaks his legs with a hammer",
    "C": "Poisons him",
    "D": "Tramples him with a horse",
    "Description": "When Bran climbs a tower and witnesses Jaime having sex with his twin sister Cersei, Jaime pushes Bran from the high window to conceal their incest."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What Dothraki warlord does Daenerys Targaryen marry?",
    "Answer": "Khal Drogo",
    "A": "Khal Moro",
    "B": "Khal Forzo",
    "C": "Khal Drogo",
    "D": "Khal Rhalko",
    "Description": "Exiled Prince Viserys Targaryen forces his sister Daenerys to marry Khal Drogo in exchange for an army to conquer Westeros and reclaim the Iron Throne."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is known as \"The King Slayer\"?",
    "Answer": "Jaime Lannister",
    "A": "Robert Baratheon",
    "B": "Khal Drogo",
    "C": "Eddard Stark",
    "D": "Jaime Lannister",
    "Description": "Robert Baratheon became king after Jaime Lannister killed \"Mad\" King Aerys Targaryen, earning Jaime the nickname, \"The King Slayer\"."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which member of Robert Baratheon's small council is a eunuch?",
    "Answer": "Varys",
    "A": "Pycelle",
    "B": "Varys",
    "C": "Petyr",
    "D": "Renly",
    "Description": "Varys, popularly known as the Spider, is the eunuch Master of Whisperers on the Baratheon small council until he is forced to flee King's Landing with Tyrion Lannister."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who has Ned Stark beheaded?",
    "Answer": "Joffrey",
    "A": "Joffrey",
    "B": "Daenerys",
    "C": "Cercei",
    "D": "Tyrion",
    "Description": "In a public hearing, Ned confesses to treason and publicly affirms Joffrey is the rightful heir. However, rather than sparing Ned's life as negotiated, the vengeful Joffrey has him decapitated."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of Craster's daughters does Samwell Tarly befriend?",
    "Answer": "Gilly",
    "A": "Sissy",
    "B": "Morag",
    "C": "Gilly",
    "D": "Tully",
    "Description": "When Samwell first encounters Gilly, she is pregnant with the incestuous child of her own father. Later, when the Night's Watch mutiny, Samwell helps her escape Craster's Keep with her son."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What plays a key role at the Battle of Blackwater?",
    "Answer": "Wildfire",
    "A": "Firebird",
    "B": "Wildfire",
    "C": "Bushfire",
    "D": "Firestorm",
    "Description": "Wildfire is a flammable liquid created and controlled by the Alchemists' Guild, an ancient society of learned men based in the city of King's Landing. Tyrion has eight thousand jars of wildfire loaded onto a single ship that is sent to meet the invading fleet. When Bronn ignites the ship with a flaming arrow, it detonates in a massive explosion that pulverizes most of Stannis' ships."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which character is the first to kill a White Walker?",
    "Answer": "Samwell Tarly",
    "A": "Samwell Tarly",
    "B": "Arya Stark",
    "C": "Jon Snow",
    "D": "Meera",
    "Description": "Trying to protect Gilly and her son, Sam stabs a White Walker with his Dragonglass dagger. The Walker howls in pain as its whole body begins to freeze from the point at which he was stabbed. It falls to its knees and shatters, leaving nothing behind but white dust and the dagger."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the \"King Beyond the Wall\"?",
    "Answer": "Mance Rayder",
    "A": "Tormund Giantsbane",
    "B": "Mance Rayder",
    "C": "Varamyr Sixskins",
    "D": "Ygon Oldfather",
    "Description": "Before serving as the leader of the Free Folk, holding the title of \"King Beyond the Wall\", Mance Rayder was once a noted ranger of the Night's Watch."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What band of warrior-eunuchs does Daenerys recruit for her army?",
    "Answer": "The unsullied",
    "A": "The unsullied",
    "B": "The Untarnished",
    "C": "The Unbroken",
    "D": "The Unstained",
    "Description": "Trained for battle from the age of five, the Unsullied, are said to be among the finest soldiers in the world. Daenerys buys them from the slaver Kraznys for one dragon. Once the deal is struck, she commands the Unsullied to kill their former masters and has her dragon burn Kraznys alive. She then frees the Unsullied, who follow her willingly."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who do the Unsullied choose as their commander?",
    "Answer": "Grey Worm",
    "A": "Black Fist",
    "B": "Dog Killer",
    "C": "Grey Worm",
    "D": "White Rat",
    "Description": "The Unsullied officers select Grey Worm to act as their official commander. When he reports his election to Daenerys, she finds his name--given to him by the Good Masters to remind him of his lowly status--distasteful. She tells him that the Unsullied may take new names, but Grey Worm chooses to keep his. He considers it lucky since it was the name he had when Daenerys set him free."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who betrays Robb Stark at the Red Wedding?",
    "Answer": "Walder Frey",
    "A": "Balon Greyjoy",
    "B": "Walder Frey",
    "C": "Hoster Tully",
    "D": "Randyll Tarly",
    "Description": "The Red Wedding is a massacre that takes place during the War of the Five Kings, arranged by Lord Walder Frey as revenge against Robb Stark, ruling King in the North, for breaking the marriage pact between House Stark and House Frey."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What new name does Ramsay Snow give Theon?",
    "Answer": "Reek",
    "A": "Slop",
    "B": "Much",
    "C": "Crud",
    "D": "Reek",
    "Description": "Following the successful capture of Winterfell from the Ironborn, Ramsay holds Theon captive and subjects him to gruesome tortures to break him into loyal submission, ultimately renaming him \"Reek."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What kind of pet does Captain Barbossa have?",
    "Answer": "Monkey",
    "A": "Alligator",
    "B": "Dog",
    "C": "Parrot",
    "D": "Monkey",
    "Description": "Barbossa has a pet monkey, which he has mockingly named \"Jack\" after his old captain."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was The Fast and the Furious based on?",
    "Answer": "Magazine Article",
    "A": "Documentary",
    "B": "Magazine Article",
    "C": "Short Story",
    "D": "Novel",
    "Description": "The May 1998 issue of Vibe magazine featured an article by Ken Li titled \"Racer X\" that chronicled the illegal street racing circuit operating in New York City. Producers optioned the article for a movie adaptation that became The Fast and the Furious."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which character in The Godfather is known as \"The Turk\"?",
    "Answer": "Virgil Sollozzo",
    "A": "Carlo Rizzi",
    "B": "Tom Hagen",
    "C": "Emilio Barzini",
    "D": "Virgil Sollozzo",
    "Description": "Rival racketeer Virgil Sollozzo is known as \"The Turk\" because he owns poppy fields in Turkey."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What secret service agency does 007 work for?",
    "Answer": "MI6",
    "A": "MI8",
    "B": "MI5",
    "C": "MI6",
    "D": "MI7",
    "Description": "Formed in 1909 as a section of the Secret Service Bureau specializing in foreign intelligence, the existence of MI6 (Military Intelligence Section 6) was not officially acknowledged until 1994."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the first James Bond movie?",
    "Answer": "Dr. No",
    "A": "Casino Royale",
    "B": "On Her Majesty's Secret Service",
    "C": "Dr. No",
    "D": "For Your Eyes Only",
    "Description": "Adapted from Fleming's novel of the same name, Dr. No (1962) featured Sean Connery as secret agent 007 and would be the first in a long line of successful Bond flicks. Connery would reprise his role in five more films, for a total of six appearances as James Bond. According to some reports, he turned down a then unheard of sum of $5.5 Million to appear in a seventh film."
  }
]
